These are four of my favorite low tech
devices.
Previously, you guys liked the video
that I did [music] about my top five buy
for life items and also my top favorite
niche tech items that have improved my
life. So, I thought in this video I
would share one of my favorite
categories of [music] niche technology,
which are inc devices. If you're not
familiar with Inc devices, this is what
a regular display looks like. [music]
And this is an e display. So, what makes
e- in devices so special is that
compared to regular screens, they
literally emit no light. So, it [music]
looks like actual paper when you're just
looking at it. And this makes it really
nice to read things, to take notes on it
or for displaying information. Like
there's no eye strain, there's no blue
light that could disrupt your security
rhythm. And there aren't [music] super
fast refresh rates. So, in devices, they
kind of remove a lot of the negative
aspects of traditional screens. So
eating screens have actually been around
for a long time now, but it's only
recently in the past few years that
there's been a lot more companies
actually innovating and improving the
technology. And there's also a trend
towards using these screens for things
like reading books and taking notes
because it's a lot nicer than using a
regular [music] screen. And I also just
see it more in my daily life now. Like I
see it in the bus stop. They use an
eating screen and even the [music]
supermarket. Personally, I think eating
screens are one of the most underrated
niche technology [music] that you can
use to help you improve your life. It
helps you integrate technology in a
better way into your own life without
having a bunch of screens [music] and a
bunch of notifications all the time. So,
in this video, I want to share with you
four of my favorite eating devices that
I have and use in my life. And hopefully
that inspires you to maybe look into
this technology more. Starting with the
first one. So, the first one is my
e-reader, the books palma. So, I've been
using this for 3 years now, and it's my
favorite way to read books. I used to
have a Kindle when I was in high school
and I had that for about 10 years, but
three years ago I upgraded to this one
and I much prefer this one over a Kindle
for a few reasons. First of all, Kindle
recently has made a few updates that
makes it harder for you to own your own
books. Like they made it so that older
versions of Kindles were no longer
supported and you were forced to buy a
new one. [music] And also they made it
really difficult to upload or download
books that you have purchased. [music]
So, one of the reasons I like the book
helmet is because it runs Android. And
so, it means that you can [music] really
customize it however you want and
install any apps that you want. And so,
there's not really ever going to be a
situation [music] where this thing is
just going to stop working because the
company behind it doesn't want you to
use it anymore. Probably the bigger
reason and the initial reason why I
switched to this one is because of the
form factor. So, a Kindle is kind of
bulky and like a traditional e-reader is
kind of bulky. It's like kind of like
the size of a book. And this one is a
phone form factor. So, it's really nice
to hold and because I put like a Mag
Safe thing on the back of it, if I'm in
bed, I can easily just like lie down and
read with this. And it really helps me
read more often because it's just easier
to use and it's a form factor that
[music] I'm used to. You might say that
you can just read books on your phone,
and I would agree with you. [music] But
if you compare the experience of reading
a book on your phone compared to reading
a book on this, it's just way nicer to
read on this. And I can actually read
books for several hours on this, like
especially if I'm on a train or an
airplane versus my phone. Like on my
phone, if I read for more than 30
minutes, I kind of get eye strain. And
especially in public transportation,
it's really hard to read on my phone
without it like really creating pretty
significant eye strain. In the past,
I've also used this device as a dopamine
detox device. When I don't want to bring
my phone out, I can just bring this and
still have access to messaging apps, AI
apps, or maps. And depending on the
version you get, you can also get a SIM
card [music] to get data on this. Of
course, I still really like reading
physical books. But a lot of times with
physical books, it's extremely [music]
bulky and really hard to read. And it's
also hard to read multiple books at a
time, which is what I do a lot on this
device. And if you travel or you move
around a lot, it's not that realistic to
have a collection of physical books. If
you study any languages, this is also
nice because you can just, you know, tap
to look up any words or install
different apps to read different types
of content. Like you can even read manga
on this device. For the most part, I
only use this at home and when I'm
traveling. I did make a video on my
setup with the books palm a while back
if you want to check that out. So, the
second device I want to share is called
the [music]
Treminal. This is basically a picture
frame that is an eating device that you
can set up to display anything that you
want and it will just refresh
periodically throughout the day. So, for
me, I put this on my desk. I've had this
for over a [music] year now and I just
have it show my calendar for the whole
week. So, this just makes it so that at
a glance I can see anything that I have
coming up without always having to have
the calendar app open or having
something [music] that has a lot of
features or a lot of notifications. This
is just kind of a passive thing that
I've set up once and just continue to
work. I want to say [music] that the
battery lasts a few months. I rarely
charge it and when I do charge it, it
lasts for a really long time. This one
has a stand or you can uh put on the
wall. So, right now I have it on the
wall. And [music] one underrated thing
you can do with this as well is you can
set this up with your calendar and then
gift it [music] to your family or your
partner and so they can see what your
schedule looks like. They recently came
out with a bigger one and I also [music]
decided to get that to display my
YouTube stats so I can see at a glance
without refreshing YouTube Studio.
[music] This one actually has a magnet.
So, in theory, you can put it on your
fridge, but I think my fridge, the
magnets aren't strong enough because it
keeps falling off. But the third device
that I [music] want to share is also a
device made by books and it's called the
Books Go, which [music] is a tablet. So,
this is a tablet that you can use for
reading documents, taking notes, or
using as a scratch [music] pad. So, in
terms of the OS, it's pretty much the
same as the books palm. It runs Android,
so you can customize it however you
want. Um, I actually have it connected
[music] to my server using sync thing.
So my books, my two books devices and my
server syncs all [music] the books
together. So they're all synced. So what
I mostly use this for is reading things
that are in [music] an A4 size. So for
example, textbooks, documents, and sheet
[music] music. So like guitar and piano.
I use this cuz you can mark it up as
well. And it's also really nice to use
as a scratch pad because the pen that it
comes with is [music] really responsive
and it's nice to draw on. So, one of the
cool things you can do with this as well
is that you can put in your own PDF, for
example, like a calendar or [music] kind
of like a planner, and then you can draw
on it and refresh it every single day.
The build [music] quality on this is
also really nice. It's really thin. The
pen has a magnetic holder right next to
it [music] and there's even a backlight.
If you wanted to keep a digital journal
where you still write by hand, I think
this is also a really good solution
[music] for me. I still prefer to
journal with paper and pen and I still
use like a a [music] regular notebook.
But if you're looking for something like
that where you can back it up and not be
scared of losing your actual journals, I
think this is a really good solution.
The main competitor that you probably
heard of to this product is the
remarkable [music] tablet. And I did
consider getting that one, but I ended
up getting this one because that one had
a bunch of upsells and monthly
subscriptions and it was less
customizable compared to this one.
[music] And it didn't seem like there
were any features that that one had that
this one didn't. And in many ways, it
seemed like this one was better. But if
you use the remarkable, I'm curious to
hear about your experience. Let me know
in the comments below. So the fourth
device I want to share is this one that
I got relatively recently. I got this
earlier this year and this is called the
XT EIN device. This is also a really
thin device. I think eating devices tend
to be on the thinner side, but this is a
really small e-reader. But the beauty of
this device is that it's small enough to
be able to stick on the back of your
phone. And it even has a magnet in it.
So, you can kind of carry it around like
that. [music] Compared to my main
e-reader, the books palm, I don't really
bring this if I'm just going out on a
normal day because it's kind of
unrealistic to bring like both my phone
and an e-reader. It's it becomes way too
bulky in [music] my pockets. And so this
kind of fills that gap where you can
easily carry this out. It can easily fit
in any of your [music] pockets and it
even sticks to the back of your phone
because it has a MagSafe uh magnet on
the back. Unlike the books, there are no
apps, so it's [music] far less
customizable. And it's really just a
folder that you can drag and drop books
onto [music] to read books on this. So
you can't really install the Kindle app
if that's how you get books, or a manga
app if you read manga. So, I would only
recommend this device for somebody
that's really comfortable getting their
own ebooks, uh, really comfortable with
getting ebooks onto this device, whereas
the books is a much easier device to set
up and [music] read books immediately. I
did install a custom OS on the XT in
[music]
it just makes it slightly more
customizable with the lock screen. I can
make it show the cover or just the page
[music] that I'm reading. And besides
that, there's pretty much no difference.
Using this kind of makes me nostalgic
for my iPhone mini because it kind of
has that similar form factor and it
reminds me that this is the ideal form
factor of a phone. So, I'm looking
forward to foldable phones where I think
it's going to get smaller [music] again.
But yeah, this is a pretty neat little
device. I've also seen some people
combine their wallet in this device into
kind of like a biffold wallet. So, that
also seems pretty interesting. But yeah,
that's pretty much it for my favorite
ink devices. Let me know what you
thought of this video. Let me know what
you thought of eat in devices if you use
them and whether or not you like to try
them. But also let me know what types of
videos you would want me to make next.
Like do you want me to make more tech
compilations or [music] do you want me
to make other stuff like other stuff I
made on the channel? Let me know what
other videos on my channel that you've
liked that you would like me to make
more of. [music] But yeah, I'm going to
try to respond to all the comments and
I'll see you there and I'll see you in
the next video. Let's get [music] it.